An extraordinary encounter with another human being.
Powder is a drama, fantasy film directed by Victor Salva.
Harassed by classmates who won't accept his shocking appearance, a
shy young man known as "Powder" struggles to fit in.
But the cruel taunts stop when Powder displays a mysterious
power that allows him to do incredible things.
This phenomenon changes the lives of all those around him
in ways they never could have imagined.
Jessie Caldwell, played by Mary Steenburgen.
Jeremy 'Powder' Reed, played by Sean Patrick Flanery.
Sheriff Doug Barnum, played by Lance Henriksen.
Donald Ripley, played by Jeff Goldblum.
Deputy Harley Duncan, played by Brandon Smith.
John Box, played by Bradford Tatum.
Powder is a 1995 American science fiction drama film
written and directed by Victor Salva.
It stars Mary Steenburgen, Sean Patrick Flanery,
Lance Henriksen, and Jeff Goldblum.
Flanery plays the title character, a young albino man with an
incredible intellect and supernatural powers.
The film was produced by Walt Disney Studios
through its Hollywood Pictures label.
Filming took place in Texas around suburbs of
Houston, San Antonio, and Austin, Texas.
The production was controversial due to Salva's prior conviction for child sex
abuse, which prompted a boycott against the film led by his victim.
Powder was released October 27, 1995.
It received mixed reviews, but was a commercial success,
grossing $30.9 million on a $9.5 million budget.
The film explores themes of teenage boy, held at gunpoint,
teacher student relationship, albino, fainting.
The tone is emotional.